export const revision = [
  {
    level: "National Parks",
    topic: "SSC CGL",
    totalQuestions: 10,
    perQuestionScore: 2,
    questions: [
      {
        question: "Tadoba national is located in",
        choices: ["Maharastra", "Uttar Prasesh", "Tamil Nadu", "Uttarakhand"],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "Maharastra",
        extradetails:
          "  Tadoba National Park is located in Chandrapur district of Maharastra. It is the largest park of Maharastra, and oldest National Park.",
      },
      {
        question: "The Silent Valley National Park is in",
        choices: ["Uttarakhand", "Odisha", "Himachal Pradesh", "Kerala"],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "Kerala",
        extradetails:
          "Silent Valley National Park is located in the Nilgiri Hills in Kerala, India. It was established on 15 November 1984.",
      },
      {
        question: "The Pin Valley National Park is located in",
        choices: ["Uttarakhand", "Odisha", "Himachal Pradesh", "Kerala"],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "Himachal Pradesh",
        extradetails:
          "Pin Valley National Park is located in Lahaul and Spiti district of Himachal Pradesh. It is famous for endangered Snow leopards. Pin Valley National Park was established in 1958.",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which of these is the National Park located in Uttar Pradesh",
        choices: [
          "Mollem National Park",
          "Dudhwa National Park",
          "Bandipur National Park",
          "Sariska National Park",
        ],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "Dudhwa National Park",
        extradetails:
          "Dudhwa National Park is located in Uttar Pradesh's Kheri and Lakhimpur Districts. It was established in 1977 as a part of Dushwa Tiger reserve.",
      },
      {
        question: "Sariska National Park is located in",
        choices: ["Maharastra", "Odisha", "Manipur", "Rajasthan"],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "Rajasthan",
        extradetails:
          "Sariska Tiger Reserve is a National Park located in Alwar District of Rajasthan.",
      },
      {
        question: "Identify the National Park located in Jammu and Kashmir",
        choices: [
          "Salim Ali National Park",
          "Hemis National Park",
          "Bandipur National Park",
          "Dudhwa",
        ],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "Salim Ali National Park",
        extradetails:
          "Salim Ali national Park is located in Srinagar, Jammu and Kashmir. Salim ali national Park is also known as City forest national park. It is named after Indian Ornithologist and Bird-Lover Salim Ali.",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Largest National Park, i.e. Hemis National Park is Located in",
        choices: ["Arunachal Padesh", "Uttarakhand", "Laddakh", "Assam"],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "Laddakh",
        extradetails:
          "Hemis national Park, located in Leh District of Laddakh is the largest National Park of India. Hemis National Park is famous for Snow leopards and was established in 1981.",
      },
      {
        question: "Kuchenjuga National Park is located in",
        choices: ["Maharastra", "Sikkim", "Manipur", "Assam"],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "Sikkim",
        extradetails:
          "Kunchenjunga national park is located in Sikkim. It is also called Kunchenjunga Biosphere Reserve. It is the first Mixed Heritage site in UNESCO World Heritage sites list. Kunchenjunga National Park was established in 1977.",
      },
      {
        question: "National Park located in Uttarakhand is",
        choices: [
          "Panna National Park",
          "Nanda Devi National Park",
          "Mollem National Park",
          "Hemis National Park",
        ],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "Nanda Devi National Park",
        extradetails:
          "Nanda Devi National Park is located in Chamoli Garhwal district of Uttarakhand. Nanda Devi National Park was Established in 1982.",
      },
      {
        question: "Largest National Park in Madhya Pradesh is",
        choices: [
          "Kanha Tiger Reserve",
          "Satpura National Park",
          "Pench National Park",
          "Van Vihar National Park",
        ],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "Kanha Tiger Reserve",
        extradetails:
          "Kanha Tiger reserve is a national Park located in Madhya Pradesh. It has Tigers, jackals, and wild pigs. It was established in 1955",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which national park is known for its population of Bengal Tigers?",
        choices: [
          "Jim Corbett National Park",
          "The Sundarbans National Park",
          "Periyar National Park",
          "Ranthambore National Park",
        ],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "The Sundarbans National Park",
        extradetails:
          "The Sundarbans National Park, located in West Bengal, is known for its population of Bengal Tigers and is a popular tourist destination.",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which national park is home to the Great Indian One-Horned Rhinoceros?",
        choices: [
          "Sundarbans National Park",
          "Bandhavgarh National Park",
          "Kanha National Park",
          "Kaziranga National Park",
        ],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "Kaziranga National Park",
        extradetails:
          "Kaziranga National Park, located in Assam, is famous for its population of the Great Indian One-Horned Rhinoceros and is a UNESCO World Heritage Site.",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which national park is known for its population of Asiatic Lions?",
        choices: [
          "Gir National Park",
          "Sundarbans National Park",
          "Bandipur National Park",
          "Hemis National Park",
        ],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "Gir National Park",
        extradetails:
          "Gir National Park, located in Gujarat, is the only place in the world where Asiatic Lions are found in the wild.",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which national park is known for its population of Indian Elephants?",
        choices: [
          "Bandipur National Park",
          "Jim Corbett National Park",
          "Periyar National Park",
          "Sundarbans National Park",
        ],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "Bandipur National Park",
        extradetails:
          "Bandipur National Park, located in Karnataka, is known for its population of Indian Elephants and is a popular wildlife destination.",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which national park is known for its population of Snow Leopards?",
        choices: [
          "Hemis National Park",
          "Kaziranga National Park",
          "Ranthambore National Park",
          "Jim Corbett National Park",
        ],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "Hemis National Park",
        extradetails:
          "Hemis National Park, located in Ladakh, is known for its population of Snow Leopards and is the largest national park in India.",
      },
    ],
  },

  {
    level: "River System",
    topic: "SSC CGL",
    totalQuestions: 10,
    perQuestionScore: 2,
    questions: [
      {
        question: "The Ganges River originates from which location?",
        choices: [
          "Kailash Range",
          "Yamunotri Glacier",
          "Gangotri Glacier",
          "Satopanth Glacier",
        ],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "Gangotri Glacier",
        extradetails:
          "The Ganges River originates as Bhagirathi river from the Gangotri Glacier in the Himalayas.When Bhagirathi river meets Alaknanda river at Dev Paryag, the combined river is known as Ganga. Its length is 2525km. It is one of the most important rivers in India.",
      },
      {
        question: "Which river is known as 'Sorrow of Bihar'?",
        choices: ["Ganges", "Yamuna", "Kosi", "Brahmaputra"],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "Kosi",
        extradetails:
          "The Kosi River is known as the 'Sorrow of Bihar' due to its frequent flooding, which causes significant damage to the region.",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Brahmaputra River is primarily associated with which region?",
        choices: ["Assam Valley", "Punjab", "Ganges Delta", "Western Ghats"],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "Assam Valley",
        extradetails:
          "The Brahmaputra River flows through the Assam Valley and is a major river in the northeastern region of India. Brahmaputra river originates from lake Mansarovar in Tibbet where it is called Tsangpo.",
      },
      {
        question: "Which river is the longest in Peninsular India?",
        choices: ["Godavari", "Yamuna", "Ganges", "Brahmaputra"],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "Godavari",
        extradetails:
          "The Godavari River is the longest peninsular river in India, flowing across central and southern India.",
      },
      {
        question: "The Yamuna River is a tributary of which major river?",
        choices: ["Ganges", "Godavari", "Brahmaputra", "Kaveri"],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "Ganges",
        extradetails:
          "The Yamuna River is a major tributary of the Ganges River and flows through northern India. It originates from Yamunotri Glacier in Uttarakhnad.",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which river forms the border between India and Pakistan in the Punjab region?",
        choices: ["Chenab", "Jhelum", "Ravi", "Sutlej"],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "Chenab",
        extradetails:
          "The Chenab River forms part of the border between India and Pakistan in the Punjab region.",
      },
      {
        question: "The Narmada River flows into which body of water?",
        choices: [
          "Bay of Bengal",
          "Arabian Sea",
          "Indian Ocean",
          "Andaman Sea",
        ],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "Arabian Sea",
        extradetails:
          "The Narmada River flows westward and empties into the Arabian Sea.",
      },
      {
        question: "Which river is known as 'Dakshina Ganga'?",
        choices: ["Krishna", "Kaveri", "Godavari", "Mahanadi"],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "Godavari",
        extradetails:
          "The Godavari River is often referred to as the 'Dakshina Ganga' or 'Vriddh Ganga' due to its significance in southern India.",
      },
      {
        question: "Which river is the main source of the Indus River?",
        choices: ["Zanskar", "Jhelum", "Chenab", "Ravi"],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "Zanskar",
        extradetails:
          "The Zanskar River is one of the main sources of the Indus River, originating from the Tibetan Plateau.",
      },
      {
        question: "Which river is famous for its delta, the Sundarbans?",
        choices: ["Sabarmati", "Brahmaputra", "Godavari", "Kaveri"],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "Brahmaputra",
        extradetails:
          "The Brahmaputra River forms the Sundarbans delta, which is known for its rich biodiversity and mangrove forests.",
      },
      {
        question: "Which river is known as the 'Lifeline of Sikkim'?",
        choices: ["Krishna", "Godavari", "Cauvery", "Teesta"],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "Teesta",
        extradetails:
          "The Cauvery River is often referred to as the 'Lifeline of Sikkim' due to its importance in providing water for irrigation and drinking purposes in the region.",
      },
      {
        question: "Which river is known as the 'Sorrow of Bengal'?",
        choices: ["Brahmaputra", "Indus", "Yangtze", "Damodar"],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "Damodar",
        extradetails:
          "The Damodar is often referred to as the 'Sorrow of Bengal' due to its history of devastating floods.",
      },
      {
        question: "Which river is the longest in Africa?",
        choices: ["Nile", "Congo", "Niger", "Zambezi"],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "Nile",
        extradetails:
          "The Nile River is the longest river in Africa, flowing through multiple countries including Egypt, Sudan, and Uganda.",
      },
      {
        question: "Which river is known as the 'Yellow River'?",
        choices: ["Yangtze", "Mekong", "Ganges", "Huang He"],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "Huang He",
        extradetails:
          "The Huang He, also known as the Yellow River, is the second-longest river in China and is named after the yellowish-brown sediment it carries.",
      },
      {
        question: "Which river is known as the 'Sorrow of Bihar'?",
        choices: ["Kosi", "Son", "Yamuna", "Tungabhadra"],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "Kosi",
        extradetails:
          "The Kosi River is often referred to as the 'Sorrow of Bihar' due to the floods caused by river in parts of Bihar.",
      },
      {
        question: "Which river is known as the 'River of Kings'?",
        choices: ["Thames", "Seine", "Danube", "Chao Phraya"],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "Chao Phraya",
        extradetails:
          "The Chao Phraya River in Thailand is often called the 'River of Kings' due to its historical and cultural significance to the country.",
      },
    ],
  },
  {
    level: "Quick Revision 01",
    topic: "SSC CGL",
    totalQuestions: 10,
    perQuestionScore: 2,
    questions: [
      {
        question: "Who was the founder of the Maurya Dynasty?",
        choices: ["Ashoka", "Chandragupta Maurya", "Bindusara", "Kanishka"],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "Chandragupta Maurya",
      },
      {
        question: "Which state in India is known as the 'Land of Five Rivers'?",
        choices: ["Uttar Pradesh", "Punjab", "Haryana", "Bihar"],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "Punjab",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The President of India is elected for a term of how many years?",
        choices: ["4 years", "5 years", "6 years", "7 years"],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "5 years",
      },
      {
        question:
          "If a sum of Rs. 5000 amounts to Rs. 6500 in 2 years at simple interest, what is the rate of interest per annum?",
        choices: ["10%", "12%", "15%", "20%"],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "15%",
      },
      {
        question:
          "In a certain code language, 'BRAIN' is written as 'AQZHM'. How will 'HEART' be written in the same code?",
        choices: ["GDZQS", "GDSZQ", "GDRZS", "GDSRQ"],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "GDZQS",
      },
      {
        question: "Choose the correct synonym for the word 'Inevitable'.",
        choices: ["Avoidable", "Optional", "Unavoidable", "Doubtful"],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "Unavoidable",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which element is essential for the formation of bones and teeth?",
        choices: ["Iron", "Calcium", "Potassium", "Sodium"],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "Calcium",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which battle led to the establishment of British rule in India?",
        choices: [
          "Battle of Plassey",
          "Battle of Panipat",
          "Battle of Haldighati",
          "Battle of Buxar",
        ],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "Battle of Plassey",
      },
      {
        question: "Which mountain range separates Europe from Asia?",
        choices: ["Alps", "Himalayas", "Ural", "Rockies"],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "Ural",
      },
      {
        question: "What is the chemical formula for common salt?",
        choices: ["HCl", "NaCl", "KCl", "CaCl2"],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "NaCl",
      },
    ],
  },
  {
    level: "Quick Revision 02",
    topic: "SSC CGL",
    totalQuestions: 10,
    perQuestionScore: 2,
    questions: [
      {
        question: "Who among the following introduced the Doctrine of Lapse?",
        choices: [
          "Lord Canning",
          "Lord Dalhousie",
          "Lord Ripon",
          "Lord Curzon",
        ],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "Lord Dalhousie",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which Indian state shares the longest border with Bangladesh?",
        choices: ["Assam", "West Bengal", "Tripura", "Meghalaya"],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "West Bengal",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which Article of the Indian Constitution deals with the protection of life and personal liberty?",
        choices: ["Article 19", "Article 20", "Article 21", "Article 22"],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "Article 21",
      },
      {
        question: "What is the square root of 1444?",
        choices: ["36", "38", "40", "42"],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "38",
      },
      {
        question:
          "If A is coded as Z, B as Y, and so on, how is the word 'CODE' written in that code?",
        choices: ["XLMW", "XKHV", "XLWV", "XLHV"],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "XLWV",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Identify the incorrect part of the following sentence: 'The team have performed excellently throughout the tournament.'",
        choices: [
          "The team",
          "have performed",
          "excellently",
          "throughout the tournament",
        ],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "have performed",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which part of the human brain is responsible for balance and coordination?",
        choices: [
          "Cerebrum",
          "Cerebellum",
          "Medulla Oblongata",
          "Hypothalamus",
        ],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "Cerebellum",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Treaty of Alinagar was signed in 1757 between the British East India Company and whom?",
        choices: [
          "Tipu Sultan",
          "Siraj ud-Daulah",
          "Nawab of Oudh",
          "Marathas",
        ],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "Siraj ud-Daulah",
      },
      {
        question: "Which ocean is the smallest in the world?",
        choices: [
          "Indian Ocean",
          "Arctic Ocean",
          "Atlantic Ocean",
          "Southern Ocean",
        ],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "Arctic Ocean",
      },
      {
        question: "Which vitamin is known as ascorbic acid?",
        choices: ["Vitamin A", "Vitamin B", "Vitamin C", "Vitamin D"],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "Vitamin C",
      },
    ],
  },
  {
    level: "Constitution of India",
    topic: "SSC CGL",
    totalQuestions: 10,
    perQuestionScore: 2,
    questions: [
      {
        question: "Who is known as the 'Architect of the Indian Constitution'?",
        choices: [
          "B.R. Ambedkar",
          "Jawaharlal Nehru",
          "Mahatma Gandhi",
          "Sardar Vallabhbhai Patel",
        ],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "B.R. Ambedkar",
        extradetails:
          "B.R. Ambedkar is known as the 'Architect of the Indian Constitution' for his pivotal role in drafting and shaping the Constitution of India.",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which article of the Indian Constitution deals with the Right to Equality?",
        choices: ["Article 14", "Article 19", "Article 21", "Article 25"],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "Article 14",
        extradetails:
          "Article 14 of the Indian Constitution guarantees the Right to Equality, which includes equality before the law and equal protection of the law for all individuals.",
      },
      {
        question: "Who has the power to amend the Indian Constitution?",
        choices: ["Parliament", "President", "Supreme Court", "Prime Minister"],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "Parliament",
        extradetails:
          "The power to amend the Indian Constitution lies with the Parliament, which consists of the President, the Rajya Sabha (Council of States), and the Lok Sabha (House of the People).",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which fundamental right is considered the 'Heart and Soul' of the Indian Constitution?",
        choices: [
          "Right to Freedom of Speech and Expression",
          "Right to Equality",
          "Right to Life and Personal Liberty",
          "Right to Constitutional Remedies",
        ],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "Right to Constitutional Remedies",
        extradetails:
          "The Right to Constitutional Remedies (Article 32) is considered the 'Heart and Soul' of the Indian Constitution as it provides individuals with the right to move the Supreme Court for the enforcement of their fundamental rights.",
      },
      {
        question: "Who appoints the Chief Justice of India?",
        choices: [
          "President",
          "Prime Minister",
          "Supreme Court Judges",
          "Chief Justice of India",
        ],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "President",
        extradetails:
          "The Chief Justice of India is appointed by the President of India, in consultation with the other judges of the Supreme Court and the High Courts.",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which article of the Indian Constitution deals with the Right to Education?",
        choices: ["Article 14", "Article 19", "Article 21A", "Article 25"],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "Article 21A",
        extradetails:
          "Article 21A of the Indian Constitution guarantees the Right to Education, which ensures free and compulsory education for children between the ages of 6 and 14 years.",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Who has the power to declare a law unconstitutional in India?",
        choices: ["President", "Prime Minister", "Supreme Court", "Parliament"],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "Supreme Court",
        extradetails:
          "The Supreme Court of India has the power to declare a law unconstitutional if it violates any provision of the Indian Constitution.",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which amendment to the Indian Constitution introduced the Right to Education as a fundamental right?",
        choices: [
          "42nd Amendment",
          "44th Amendment",
          "86th Amendment",
          "93rd Amendment",
        ],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "86th Amendment",
        extradetails:
          "The 86th Amendment to the Indian Constitution, passed in 2002, introduced the Right to Education as a fundamental right under Article 21A.",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which amendment to the Indian Constitution introduced the Right to Property as a legal right?",
        choices: [
          "42nd Amendment",
          "44th Amendment",
          "86th Amendment",
          "36th Amendment",
        ],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "44th Amendment",
        extradetails:
          "The 44th Amendment to the Indian Constitution, passed in 1978, removed the Right to Property as a fundamental right and made it a legal right.",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which article of the Indian Constitution deals with the Right to Freedom of Speech and Expression?",
        choices: ["Article 14", "Article 19(1)(a)", "Article 21", "Article 25"],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "Article 19(1)(a)",
        extradetails:
          "Article 19(1)(a) of the Indian Constitution guarantees the Right to Freedom of Speech and Expression, which includes the freedom to express one's opinions, beliefs, and ideas.",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Who has the power to remove the President of India from office?",
        choices: [
          "Prime Minister",
          "Supreme Court",
          "Parliament",
          "Chief Justice of India",
        ],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "Parliament",
        extradetails:
          "The President of India can be removed from office by a process of impeachment initiated by the Parliament, if he/she is found guilty of violating the Constitution.",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which article of the Indian Constitution deals with the Right to Life and Personal Liberty?",
        choices: ["Article 14", "Article 19", "Article 21", "Article 25"],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "Article 21",
        extradetails:
          "Article 21 of the Indian Constitution guarantees the Right to Life and Personal Liberty, which includes the right to live with dignity and freedom from arbitrary arrest or detention.",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which amendment to the Indian Constitution introduced the Right to Information as a fundamental right?",
        choices: [
          "42nd Amendment",
          "44th Amendment",
          "86th Amendment",
          "93rd Amendment",
        ],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "93rd Amendment",
        extradetails:
          "The 93rd Amendment to the Indian Constitution, passed in 2005, introduced the Right to Information as a fundamental right under Article 19(1)(a).",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which article of the Indian Constitution deals with the Right to Freedom of Religion?",
        choices: ["Article 14", "Article 19", "Article 21", "Article 25"],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "Article 25",
        extradetails:
          "Article 25 of the Indian Constitution guarantees the Right to Freedom of Religion, which includes the freedom to profess, practice, and propagate one's religion.",
      },
      {
        question: "Who has the power to appoint the Prime Minister of India?",
        choices: ["President", "Vice President", "Supreme Court", "Parliament"],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "President",
        extradetails:
          "The President of India has the power to appoint the Prime Minister of India, who is usually the leader of the majority party in the Lok Sabha.",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which amendment to the Indian Constitution introduced the Right to Education as a fundamental right?",
        choices: [
          "42nd Amendment",
          "44th Amendment",
          "86th Amendment",
          "93rd Amendment",
        ],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "86th Amendment",
        extradetails:
          "The 86th Amendment to the Indian Constitution, passed in 2002, introduced the Right to Education as a fundamental right under Article 21A.",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which amendment to the Indian Constitution introduced the Right to Property as a legal right?",
        choices: [
          "42nd Amendment",
          "44th Amendment",
          "86th Amendment",
          "36th Amendment",
        ],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "44th Amendment",
        extradetails:
          "The 44th Amendment to the Indian Constitution, passed in 1978, removed the Right to Property as a fundamental right and made it a legal right.",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which article of the Indian Constitution deals with the Right to Freedom of Speech and Expression?",
        choices: ["Article 14", "Article 19(1)(a)", "Article 21", "Article 25"],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "Article 19(1)(a)",
        extradetails:
          "Article 19(1)(a) of the Indian Constitution guarantees the Right to Freedom of Speech and Expression, which includes the freedom to express one's opinions, beliefs, and ideas.",
      },

      {
        question:
          "Which article of the Indian Constitution deals with the Right to Life and Personal Liberty?",
        choices: ["Article 14", "Article 19", "Article 21", "Article 25"],
        type: "MCQs",
        correctAnswer: "Article 21",
      },
    ],
  },
];
